Guide to the Nina Berberova Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1924-1993; Series I; 11.0' (22 boxes)
  - Czapski, Jozef, 1958 Jul 22 (Box 6, Folder 128)
  - "D" general, 1970-91, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 129)
  - D'Amico, M., 1987 May 16 (Box 6, Folder 130)
  - Davies, Marianne, 1987-92 (Box 6, Folder 131)
  - Davies, Richard, 1977-89, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 132)
  - Davydov, Sergei, 1981-83, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 133)
  - Davydova, Kseniia IUr'evna, 1983-88, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 134-135)
  - Dees, Benjamin, 1965-77, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 136-137)
  - Deotto, Patrizia, 1985-93, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 138)
  - Derbyshire, William, 1967-91, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 139)
  - Dickson, Colin, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 140)
  - Dictionary of International Biography, 1977, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 141)
  - Dobrovol'skaia, IUliia, 1983-92, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 142)
  - Dobuzhinskaia, Elizaveta Osipovna, 1958 Jan 18 (Box 7, Folder 143)
  - Dobuzhinskii, Rostislav Mstislavovich, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 144)
  - Donskaia, Sofiia, 1984-90, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 145)
  - Dostoevskaia, Ekaterina, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 146)
  - Douglas, Kenneth, 1965-66 (Box 7, Folder 147)
  - Dovlatov, Sergei, 1980-86, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 148)
  - Druzhba narodov, 1989-90 (Box 7, Folder 149)
  - Dutton, Richard, 1980-89, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 150)
  - "E" general, 1989-92 (Box 7, Folder 151)
  - Edgerton, William B., 1961-74 (Box 7, Folder 152)
  - Editions Atheneum (Publishers), 1983-89 (Box 7, Folder 153)
  - Efimov, Igor' Markovich, 1988-89 (Box 7, Folder 154)
  - Elagin, Ivan, 1966-67, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 155)
  - Eliot, T.S.
    See: Faber & Faber (Publishers), Box 8, folder 168
  - Elisman, IUrii L'vovich, 1988 Apr 4 (Box 7, Folder 156)
  - Elnitsky, Svetlana, 1991 Jan (Box 7, Folder 157)
  - Elsworth, John, 1969-82 (Box 7, Folder 158)
  - Emerson, Caryl, 1987-88 (Box 7, Folder 159)
  - English, Maurice, 1979-82 (Box 7, Folder 160)
  - E. P. Dutton (Publishers), 1984 (Box 8, Folder 161)
  - Erevanskii universitet, 1969, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 162)
  - Erlich, Victor, 1961-84 (Box 8, Folder 163)
  - Ermolaev, Herman, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 164)
  - Ernst, Sergei Fedorovich, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 165)
  - Etkind, Efim Grigor'evich, 1975-80, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 166)
  - "F" general, 1989-91 (Box 8, Folder 167)
  - Faber & Faber (Publishers), 1962 (Box 8, Folder 168)
  - Fagles, Robert, 1973-76, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 169)
  - Fainsod, Merle, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 170)
  - Fanger, Donald, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 171)
  - Farrar, Strauss & Giroux, 1980-81, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 172)
    See also: Faber & Faber (Publishers), Box 8, folder 168
  - Fedotov, Georgii Petrovich, 1947, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 173)
  - Fenwick, Millicent, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 174)
  - Fermani, Elisabetta, 1982-83 (Box 8, Folder 175)
  - Fessenko, Tatiana, 1965-67 (Box 8, Folder 176)
  - Field, Andrew, 1963-67 (Box 8, Folder 177)
  - Filippov, Boris Andreevich, 1961-68 (Box 8, Folder 178)
  - Filonenko, Sonia, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 179)
  - Fink, Wilhelm, 1970-80 (Box 8, Folder 180)
  - Fischer, Louis, 1964-72, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 181)
  - Fischer, George
  - Fischer, Peter A., 1968 (Box 8, Folder 182)
  - Fleishman, Lazar', 1977-90, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 183)
  - Folejewski, Zbigniew, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 184)
  - Fosdick, Dorothy, 1970-73, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 185)
  - Frampton, Kenneth, 1969 Jun 27 (Box 8, Folder 186)
  - France: Ministère de la Culture, de la Communication, des Grands Travaux et du Bicentenaire, 1989 Jun 1 (Box 8, Folder 187)
  - Frank, Joseph, 1974-85, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 188)
  - Freidin, Gregory, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 189)
  - Friedberg, Maurice, 1978-83 (Box 8, Folder 190)
  - Furstenberg, Diane von, 1989-91, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 191)
  - "G" general, 1969-93, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 192)
  - Gaes, Roger, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 193)
  - Garetto, Elda, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 194)
  - Garshin, M., 1935 Jul 1 (Box 8, Folder 195)
  - Garvin, M., 1969-92 (Box 8, Folder 196)
  - Gifford, Henry, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 197)
  - Ginzburg, Lidiia, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 198)
  - Gippius, Zinaida Nikolaevna, 1926-30, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 199)
    Includes a speech by Gippius given at Zelenaia lampa.
  - Giroud, Vincent, 1989-92, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 200)
  - Glad, John, 1977-83 (Box 8, Folder 201)
  - Gladkov, Aleksandr Konstantinovich, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 202)
    Includes letter of conveyance from Alma Law and NNB's response to her.
  - Gladkova, Tatiana, 1987 Feb 26 (Box 8, Folder 203)
  - Glasboro State College, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 204)
  - Globe Magazine, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 205)
  - Globe, Paul, 1979-81 (Box 9, Folder 206)
  - Goerner, Tatiana, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 207)
  - Gol'denveizer, Aleksei Aleksandrovich, 1961-62 (Box 9, Folder 208)
  - Gorbanevskaia, Natasha, 1981 Dec 15 (Box 9, Folder 209)
  - Gordey, Beverly, 1986-88 (Box 9, Folder 210)
  - Gordon, Karen Elizabeth, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 211)
  - Le Grand Livre du Mois, 1990-91 (Box 9, Folder 212)
  - Grani (Journal), 1983 Mar (Box 9, Folder 213)
  - Grava, Florence, 1991 Jan 16 (Box 9, Folder 214)
  - Graziadei, Caterina, 1969-93 (Box 9, Folder 215)
  - Grigoriants, Sergei, 1967-72, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 216)
  - Gromova, Tamara Vladimirovna, 1988-89, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 217)
  - Grossman, Joan Delaney, 1978-82 (Box 9, Folder 218)
  - Guerra, René, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 218a)
  - Gul', Roman, 1950-67, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 219)
    Includes one letter from Gul' to Il'ia Kovarskii.
  - Gurly, Robert, 1976-78 (Box 9, Folder 220)
  - Gurvich, Fira, 1976-92, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 221-222)
  - "H" general, 1969-92 (Box 9, Folder 223)
  - Hagglund, Roger, 1973-75 (Box 9, Folder 224)
  - Hagopian, John, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 225)
  - Hamilton, Hamish, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 226)
  - Hampshire, Stuart, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 227)
  - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, 1966-91 (Box 9, Folder 228-229)
    See also: Actes sud (Publishers), Box 1, folders 3-15
  - Hasegawa, Tsuyoshi (Box 9, Folder 230)
    See also: Nathan Smith, Box 19, folders 519-521
  - Hayes, Nicholas, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 231)
  - Hayward, Max, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 232)
  - Heim, Michael, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 233)
  - Hellman, Françoise, 1989-91 (Box 10, Folder 234)
  - Hemlock Society, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 235)
  - Hoffman, George W., 1975 (Box 10, Folder 236)
  - Hoog, Armand Hoog, Marie-Jacques, 1975-77, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 237)
  - Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace, 1975-92 (Box 10, Folder 238-241)
  - Hornstein, Yakov, 1967-70 (Box 10, Folder 242)
  - Hughes, Robert Hughes, Olga Raevsky, 1967-92, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 243)
  - Humanities Fund, 1959-62 (Box 10, Folder 244)
  - "I" general, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 245)
  - Indiana University Press, 1983 Jan 5 (Box 10, Folder 246)
  - Ingemanson, Birgitta, 1970-85 (Box 10, Folder 247)
  - Ingram Merrill Foundation, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 248)
  - Institut fur Osteuropakunde, 1963 Apr 1 (Box 10, Folder 249)
  - Instituto universitario di Bergamo, 1984, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 250)
  - International Literary Center, 1974-88, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 251)
  - IUr'eva, Aleksandra, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 252)
  - Ivanov, Georgii, 1950, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 253)
  - Ivanov-Razumnik, R. V., 1942-46 (Box 10, Folder 254)
  - Ivask, IUrii Pavlovich, 1958-62 (Box 10, Folder 255)
  - Ivich, Aleksandr, 1975-78 (Box 10, Folder 256)
  - Izvol'skaia, Elena, 1958, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 257)
  - "J" general, 1988-92 (Box 10, Folder 258)
  - Jackson, Henry M., 1970 (Box 10, Folder 259)
  - Jackson, Robert Louis, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 260)
  - Jakobson, Roman, 1972-81 (Box 10, Folder 261)
  - Janecek, Gerald, 1973-89, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 262-264)
  - Jangfeldt, Bengt, 1982-90, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 265)
  - Johnson, Brad, 1984 Apr 25 (Box 11, Folder 266)
  - Jordan, Barry D., 1979 (Box 11, Folder 267)
  - Juliar, Michael, 1980-91, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 268)
  - Jurgenson, Luba, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 269)
  - "K" general, 1969-92, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 270)
  - Kalb, Judith, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 271)
  - Kaminskaia, Dina Isakovna, 1983-88, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 272)
  - Kamp, Anna, 1986-89, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 273)
  - Kan, Sergei Kan, Alla, 1982-83, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 274)
  - Kaplan, Danielle, 1981, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 275)
  - Karlinsky, Simon, 1963-89, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 276-277)
  - Karpovich, Michael, 1946-58 (Box 11, Folder 278)
  - Karpovich, Sergei, 1980 Dec 16 (Box 11, Folder 279)
  - Kasack, Wolfgang, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 280)
  - Kassof, Allen Kassof, Ariane, 1974-88, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 281)
  - Katanian, Vasily V. Gens, Inna, 1986-89, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 282)
    See also: Bengt Jangfeldt, Box 11, folder 262
  - Katkov, George, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 283)
    See also: Nathan Smith, Box 19, folder 519
  - Katsell, Jerry, 1988 Oct 14 (Box 11, Folder 284)
  - Kellar, Suzanne, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 285)
  - Kennan, George Frost, 1962-88, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 286)
  - Kennan Institute for Advanced Russian Studies, 1978-90, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 287-289)
  - Kent, Leonard J., 1963-75, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 290)
  - Kerensky, Aleksandr Fyodorovich, 1945-65, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 291-295)
  - Kerensky, Oleg A., 1968 Jul 31 (Box 12, Folder 296)
  - Kern, Gary, 1964-80 (Box 12, Folder 297-298)
  - Ketchian, Sonia, 1989-92 (Box 12, Folder 299)
  - Khatchatrian, Vanda, 1991 Aug 6 (Box 12, Folder 300)
  - Khodasevich, Olga, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 301)
  - Khodasevich, Vladislav Felitsianovich, 1926-39 (Box 12, Folder 302-305)
  - Khomiakov, Gennadii Andreevich, 1959-61 (Box 12, Folder 306-307)
  - Kimball, Robert, 1981 Oct 5 (Box 12, Folder 308)
  - Kleckner, Robert G., 1991, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 309)
  - Klenovskii, Dmitrii Iosifovich, 1950-61 (Box 12, Folder 310)
  - Klimov, Alexis, 1971-82 (Box 12, Folder 311)
  - Kline, George Louis, 1957-82 (Box 12, Folder 312)
    Includes a copy of a letter from Kline to Isaiah Berlin, and a copy of Berlin's response.
  - Knizhnaia palata (Publishers), 1993 Mar (Box 12, Folder 313)
  - Knobelsdorff, Katia, 1987-90, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 314)
  - Koch, Stephen, 1990-91 (Box 12, Folder 315)
  - Kochevitsky, George A., 1967-89, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 316)
  - Kononov, Nikolai Mikhailovich, 1989-90 (Box 12, Folder 317)
  - Konovalov, S., 1964 (Box 12, Folder 318)
  - Kopelev, Lev Orlova, Raisa Davydovna, 1975-82, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 319)
  - Koriakov, Mikhail, 1951 Jun 15 (Box 12, Folder 320)
  - Koroleva, Nina Valerianovna, 1989-90, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 321)
  - Krassowski, Oleg, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 322)
  - Kreps, Michael, 1986-87 (Box 12, Folder 323)
  - Kudo, S., 1986-87 (Box 12, Folder 324)
  - Kul'tura (Publishers), 1991 Nov 22 (Box 12, Folder 325)
  - Kuprin, Aleksandr Ivanovich (Box 12, Folder 326)
  - Kuznetsov, Anatolii Vasil'evich, 1969-71, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 327)
  - Kuznetsova, Galina, 1965-76 (Box 12, Folder 328)
  - "L" general, 1989-90, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 329)
  - Labry, Raoul, 1947 Jul 22 (Box 13, Folder 330)
  - La Riche, William, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 331)
  - La Rivière, Sylvie de, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 332)
  - Lavrov, Aleksandr Vasil'evich, 1987-89 (Box 13, Folder 333)
  - Lebedev, Fedor, 1959-61 (Box 13, Folder 334)
  - Ledkovskaia-Astman, Marina, 1977-91 (Box 13, Folder 335)
  - Lehrman, Edgar H., 1982 (Box 13, Folder 336)
  - Leiser, Jacques, 1990 Jun 23 (Box 13, Folder 337)
  - Levin, Bernard, 1987-88 (Box 13, Folder 338)
  - Levine, Isaac Don, 1964-68 (Box 13, Folder 339)
  - Levinson, Rina, 1985, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 340)
  - Levinton, G. A., 1979-89 (Box 13, Folder 341)
  - Levitskii, Sergei Aleksandrovich, 1958 Apr 5 (Box 13, Folder 342)
  - Livshitz, Lev, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 343)
  - Lisfranc, Virginie, 1989, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 344)
  - Literary Review, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 345)
  - Literaturnaia gazeta, 1992 Apr 29 (Box 13, Folder 346)
  - Literaturnoe nasledstvo, 1969-70, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 347)
  - Litvinov, Pavel, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 348)
  - Liubarskii, Valentin, 1987 Nov (Box 13, Folder 349)
  - Live, Yusion, 1986, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 350)
  - Ljunggren, Magnus, 1988-91 (Box 13, Folder 351)
  - Lockhart, Robin Bruce, 1984-89, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 352)
  - Longmans (Publishers), 1969-82 (Box 13, Folder 353)
  - Lossev, Aleksei Vladimirovich, 1980-81 (Box 13, Folder 354)
  - Lourié, Vera, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 355)
  - Lubiannikova, Ekaterina Ivanovna, 1981-89 (Box 13, Folder 356-357)
  - Ludwig, Richard, 1971-79 (Box 13, Folder 358)
  - Luksic, Irena, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 359)
  - Lunts, Lev, 1923 Dec 21 (Box 13, Folder 360)
  - Lussy, Florence de, 1986-87, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 361)
  - "M" general, 1986-91, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 362)
  - MacArthur Foundation, 1987 May 5 (Box 13, Folder 363)
  - MacKenzie, Norman, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 364)
  - Maclean, Alan, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 365)
  - MacReady, Alan, 1957 Jan 16 (Box 13, Folder 366)
  - Magerovsky, Lev, 1967-68 (Box 13, Folder 367)
  - Maguire, Robert A., 1969-85, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 368)
  - Maison du livre étranger, 1961-66 (Box 13, Folder 369)
  - Makeeva, Irina Lavrent'evna, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 370)
  - Maksimov, Dmitrii Evgen'evich, 1966-78 (Box 13, Folder 371)
  - Malmstad, John E., 1961-92, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 372-377)
    See also: Sofiia Poliakova, Box 16, folder 453
  - Manceaux, Michel, 1987-89, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 378)
  - Marcadé, Jean-Claude Marcadé, Valentina, 1975-87 (Box 14, Folder 379)
  - Marchand, Jean-Jose, 1989, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 380)
  - Markov, Vladimir, 1965-66 (Box 14, Folder 381)
  - Markowicz, André Markowicz, Irène, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 382)
  - Maslenikov, Oleg Aleksandrovich, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 383)
  - Matheson, Nina W., 1978 (Box 14, Folder 384)
  - McCormick, Donald, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 385)
  - McFalls, Richard W., 1977 Nov 30 (Box 14, Folder 386)
  - McGraw-Hill Book Company, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 387)
  - McVay, Gordon, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 388)
  - Mel'chuk, Igor, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 389)
  - Melgunova-Stepanova, Praskov'ia Evgen'evna, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 390)
  - Melikazarian, Alexandre, 1989-90, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 391)
  - Merezhkovsky, Dmitry Sergeyevich, 1926 Jul 26 (Box 14, Folder 392)
  - Michelson, Annette, 1981-88 (Box 14, Folder 393)
  - Mickiewicz, Denis Mickiewicz, Ellen, 1968-71 (Box 14, Folder 394)
  - Middlebury College, 1980-91 (Box 14, Folder 395)
  - Miller, Jane, 1978 Mar (Box 14, Folder 396)
  - Miller, Ronald E., n.d. (Box 14, Folder 397)
  - Misslin, Anne, 1986-89 (Box 15, Folder 398-399)
  - Mitchell, James H., 1978 (Box 15, Folder 400)
  - Mitchell, Paul, 1988 Apr 12 (Box 15, Folder 401)
  - Modern Encyclopedia of Russian and Soviet Literature, 1976-77 (Box 15, Folder 402)
  - Monas, Sidney, 1967-75 (Box 15, Folder 403)
  - Le Monde, 1988 Dec 16 (Box 15, Folder 404)
  - Mosty, 1958-59 (Box 15, Folder 405)
  - Muratova, Kseniia, 1958 Jan 8 (Box 15, Folder 406)
  - "N" general, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 407)
  - Nabokov, Dominique, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 408)
  - Nabokov, Vladimir Vladimirovich, 1934-39, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 409)
  - Naginski, Isabelle, 1975-76, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 410)
  - Nappelbaum, Ida, 1968-92, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 411)
  - Naumann, Marina Turkevich, 1973, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 412)
  - Neal, Fred Warner, 1967-92, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 413)
  - Nelson, Lowry, 1971-91 (Box 15, Folder 414)
  - New York Public Library, 1962-65 (Box 15, Folder 415)
  - New York Review of Books, 1966-89, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 416)
  - New York Times, 1969-78, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 417)
  - New Yorker, 1991-93, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 418)
  - Newsday, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 419)
  - Nicolaevsky, Boris I., 1946-51 (Box 15, Folder 420)
  - Nidermiller, Nina, 1961 (Box 15, Folder 421)
  - Nikolskaia, Tatiana Chertkov, Leonid, 1972-78, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 422)
  - Niqueux, Michel, 1987-88, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 423)
  - Nivat, Georges, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 424)
  - Noir sur Blanc (Publishers), 1988-89 (Box 15, Folder 425)
  - Novyi Amerikanets, 1982-83, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 426)
  - Nyssen, Hubert
    See: Actes sud (Publishers), Box 1, folder 3
  - "O" general, 1989-92 (Box 15, Folder 427)
  - Okin, Misha, 1982-91 (Box 15, Folder 428)
  - Oktiabr', 1989 Aug 1 (Box 15, Folder 429)
  - Onassis, Jacqueline Kennedy, 1990-92, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 430)
    See also: William La Riche, Box 13, folder 331
  - Oppenheim, Lila, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 431)
  - Orlov, Sergei D., 1989 Dec 28 (Box 15, Folder 432)
  - Orlov, Vladimir Nikolaevich, 1964-75, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 433-434)
  - "P" general, 1986-93, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 435)
  - Pachmuss, Temira, 1965-82 (Box 16, Folder 436)
  - Paduch, Teresa, 1992, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 437)
  - Pantheon Books, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 438)
  - Parnis, Aleksandr Efimovich, 1992 Aug 26 (Box 16, Folder 439)
  - Patten, Arturo, 1991-92 (Box 16, Folder 440)
  - Patterson, Rod, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 441)
  - PEN American Center, 1992 Feb 12 (Box 16, Folder 442)
  - La Pensée Russe, 1950-88, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 443)
  - Perelman, Victor B., 1985 (Box 16, Folder 444)
  - Perel'muter, Vadim, 1988-92 (Box 16, Folder 445)
  - Pis'mennyi, IUrii Aleksandrovich, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 446)
  - Platek, IAkov Moiseevich, 1988-89 (Box 16, Folder 447)
  - Platone, Rossana, 1983 Apr 12 (Box 16, Folder 448)
  - Pletnev, Leonid B., 1990 Apr 12 (Box 16, Folder 449)
  - Pletneva-Boutine, Alexandra, 1988-90 (Box 16, Folder 450)
  - Pletnewa, Liusia, 1987 Apr 27 (Box 16, Folder 451)
  - Poliakov, Léon, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 452)
  - Poliakova, Sofiia Viktorovna, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 453)
  - Pollard, Alan, 1987 Oct 1 (Box 16, Folder 454)
  - Pounder, Robert, 1989-92 (Box 16, Folder 455)
  - Poznansky, Alexander, 1985-88 (Box 16, Folder 456)
  - Princeton University, 1964-92 (Box 16, Folder 457)
  - Princeton University Press, 1964-90 (Box 16, Folder 458)
  - Proffer, Carl, 1968-83 (Box 16, Folder 459)
  - Pushkarev, Sergei Germanovich, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 460)
  - "R" general, 1969-92 (Box 16, Folder 461)
  - Rabinovich, Alex, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 462)
  - Radley, Philippe, 1962-92, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 463-465)
  - RAI Corporation, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 466)
  - Randall-Petree, Deirdre, 1967-81, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 467)
  - Rannit, Alexis Rannit, Tatiana, 1961-87, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 468-469)
    See also: Box 46, folder 1077
  - Remizov, Aleksei, 1946-53 (Box 17, Folder 470)
  - Richards, Betty T., 1989 Aug 4 (Box 17, Folder 471)
  - Rice, Jim, 1983-84 (Box 17, Folder 472)
  - Rischin, Ruth, 1982-93 (Box 17, Folder 473)
  - Rockliff, Michael E., 1992 (Box 17, Folder 474)
  - Roethel, Hans, 1977-79 (Box 17, Folder 475)
  - Rogers, Tom, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 476)
  - Ronen, Omry Ronen, Irena, 1966-86, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 477-478)
  - Rosen, Natan, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 479)
  - Rudenstine, Angelica, 1991 Jul 5 (Box 17, Folder 480)
  - Russian Review, 1954-83 (Box 17, Folder 481)
  - Russica Publishers, 1980-90, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 482-483)
    See also: Actes sud (Publishers), Box 1, folder 3
    See also: Noir sur Blanc (Publishers), Box 15, folder 425
  - Russkaia mysl', 1983 Dec 1 (Box 17, Folder 484)
  - "S" general, 1926-93 (Box 17, Folder 485)
  - Scammell, Michael, 1982-83 (Box 17, Folder 486)
  - Schapiro, Efim, 1968-69 (Box 17, Folder 487)
  - Schenker, Alexander M., 1962-74 (Box 17, Folder 488)
  - Schwartz, Marian, 1981-91 (Box 17, Folder 489-491)
  - Schweitzer, Lydia, 1980-86 (Box 18, Folder 492-494)
  - Schweitzer, Viktoria Aleksandrovna, 1991 May 21 (Box 18, Folder 495)
  - Setchkarev, Margarita Aleksandrovna Setchkarev, Vsevolod Mikhailovich, 1958-81 (Box 18, Folder 496-497)
  - Shapiro, Gavriel, 1985-87 (Box 18, Folder 498)
  - Shcheglov, IUrii, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 499)
  - Sheikholeslami, Erika, 1973-89 (Box 18, Folder 500)
  - Shklovskii, Nikita, 1990 Dec 4 (Box 18, Folder 501)
  - Shmelev, Ivan, 1947-49, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 502)
  - Shtein, Emmanuil Shtein, Olga, 1971-72, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 503)
  - Shub, David, 1958 Apr 27 (Box 18, Folder 504)
  - Shuiskii, Sergei, 1984-86, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 505)
  - Sieveking, Vincent, 1967-92 (Box 18, Folder 506-510)
  - Silard, Lena, 1969, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 511)
  - Silbajoris, Frank R., 1989 (Box 18, Folder 512)
  - Simanskii, Vladislav Alekseevich, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 513)
  - Siniavskii, Andrei, 1973-75 (Box 18, Folder 514)
  - Sixsmith, Martin, 1978-79 (Box 18, Folder 515)
  - Slonim, Mark, 1969 (Box 19, Folder 516)
  - Smakov, Gennady, 1970-87, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 517-518)
  - Smith, Nathan, 1969-92 (Box 19, Folder 519-521)
  - Smolenskii, Vladimir, 1951-58 (Box 19, Folder 522)
  - Society Hill Towers, 1991-92, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 523)
  - Soiuzkinoservis, 1990 Jun 7 (Box 19, Folder 524)
  - Sokolov, Sasha, 1976-86 (Box 19, Folder 525)
  - Sonnenfeld, Albert, 1969 (Box 19, Folder 526)
  - Sorkin, Bernard R., 1979-80 (Box 19, Folder 527)
  - Souvarine, Boris, 1950-70 (Box 19, Folder 528-529)
  - Sovetskaia Muzyka, 1990 Sep 25 (Box 19, Folder 530)
  - Starr, S. Frederick Starr, Nancy, 1967-92, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 531-532)
  - Startsev, V., n.d. (Box 19, Folder 533)
  - Stein, Joseph, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 534)
  - Stephan, John, 1983-89 (Box 19, Folder 535)
  - Stepun, Fedor, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 536)
  - Stepun, Maragrita
    See: Galina Kuznetsova, Box 12, folder 328
  - Stern, Liudmila, 1981, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 537)
  - Stills Press Agency, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 538)
  - Stoliarova, Nadezhda Ivanovna, 1984 Jan 25 (Box 19, Folder 539)
  - Struve, Gleb, 1950-79 (Box 19, Folder 540-541)
  - Struve, Nikita, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 542)
  - Sumerkin, Sasha, 1979-89, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 543-544)
  - Suzukawa, M., 1990 (Box 20, Folder 545)
  - Sylvester, Richard, 1973-87, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 546-550)
    Includes responses from Chatto & Windus.
  - Szyk, Aleksandr Adol'fovich, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 551)
  - "T" general, 1990, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 552)
  - Tamarchenko, Grigory, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 553)
  - Tamirov, Akim, 1952, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 554)
  - Taranovskii, Kirill, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 555)
  - Tarasenkov, Dmitrii, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 556)
  - Task, Sergei, 1980-91, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 557)
  - Taubman, Jane A., 1983-84 (Box 20, Folder 558)
  - Tereshkovich, France, 1991 Aug 2 (Box 20, Folder 559)
  - Terrée, Emmanuel, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 560)
  - Tervonen, Kamilla, 1985-90, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 561)
  - Tevis, Anna, 1986-87, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 562)
  - Thames Television PLC, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 563)
  - Tiomkin, Dimitri, 1966-69 (Box 20, Folder 564)
  - Titov, Vladislav, 1988, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 565)
  - Tjalsma, William, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 566)
  - Todd, Albert C., 1962-63 (Box 20, Folder 567)
  - Todd, William, 1976-78, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 568)
  - Tolstaia, Aleksandra, 1954, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 569)
  - Tomlinson, Charles, 1981-83 (Box 20, Folder 570)
  - Torriglia, Anna Maria, 1991-92 (Box 20, Folder 571)
  - Townsend, Charles, 1968-88, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 572)
  - Troll', IUlia, 1982-83 (Box 21, Folder 573)
  - Troubetzkoy, Wladimir, 1991 Nov 3 (Box 21, Folder 574)
  - Tschaikovsky Foundation, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 575)
  - TSentral'nyi gosudarstvennyi arkhiv literatury i isskustva, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 576)
  - TSetlina, Mariia Samoilovna, 1953 Dec 27 (Box 21, Folder 577)
  - Turkevich, Ludmilla Buketoff, 1976 Apr 28 (Box 21, Folder 578)
  - Tusquets Editores, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 579)
  - Tyrmand, Leopold, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 580)
  - Ueland, Carol, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 581)
  - Ulianov, Nikolai Ivanovich, 1951-58, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 582)
  - UMI, 1991 Jul 22 (Box 21, Folder 583)
  - Unbegaun, Boris, 1960-69 (Box 21, Folder 584)
  - University of California, Berkeley, 1979-83, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 585)
  - University of Chicago Press, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 586)
  - University of Illinois, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 587)
  - University of Nebraska Press, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 588)
  - University of Pennsylvania, 1970-73 (Box 21, Folder 589)
  - Urnov, Fedor Urnov, Olga, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 590)
  - Ustinov, Andrey, 1993 Mar 21 (Box 21, Folder 591)
  - Ustinov, Peter, 1979 Feb 12 (Box 21, Folder 592)